<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sorts</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close</string>
    <string name="def_algorithm_name">Algorithm name</string>
    <string name="def_algorithm_description">But I must explain to you how all this mistaken idea of denouncing pleasure and praising pain was born and I will give you a complete account of the system, and expound the actual teachings of the great explorer of the truth, the master-builder of human happiness. No one rejects, dislikes, or avoids pleasure itself, because it is pleasure, but because those who do not know how to pursue pleasure rationally encounter consequences that are extremely painful. Nor again is there anyone who loves or pursues or desires to obtain pain of itself, because it is pain, but because occasionally circumstances occur in which toil and pain can procure him some great pleasure. To take a trivial example, which of us ever undertakes laborious physical exercise, except to obtain some advantage from it? But who has any right to find fault with a man who chooses to enjoy a pleasure that has no annoying consequences, or one who avoids a pain that produces no resultant pleasure?
    </string>
    <string name="desc_a_m_img_btn_go">Image Button Go</string>
    <string name="desc_a_bab_img_btn_share">Image Button Share in bottom app bar</string>
    <string name="desc_a_bab_img_btn_code">Image Button Code in bottom app bar</string>
    <string name="desc_a_bab_img_btn_description">Image Button Description in bottom app bar</string>
    <string name="desc_a_m_nav_h_img_btn_info">Image Button Info in header of navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="a_m_nd_m1_titleSample1">Algorithm name 1</string>
    <string name="a_m_nd_m1_titleSample2">Algorithm name 2</string>
    <string name="a_m_nd_m1_titleSample3">Algorithm name 3</string>
    <string name="f_code_c_debugger_code_txt_hint">Run code to see the log&#8230;</string>

    <string-array name="sorts_names">
        <item>Stupid sort</item>
        <item>Insertion sort</item>
        <item>Bubble sort</item>
        <item>Quick sort</item>
        <item>Cocktail Shaker sort</item>
        <item>Comb sort</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sorts_description">
        <item>
            This sort is a highly ineffective sorting function based on the generate and test paradigm.
            The function successively generates permutations of its input until it finds one that is sorted.
            It is not useful for sorting, but may be used for educational purposes, to contrast it with more efficient
            algorithms. Two versions of the function exist: a deterministic version that enumerates all permutations
            until it hits a sorted one, and a randomized version that randomly permutes its input.
            An analogy for the working of the latter version is to sort a deck of cards by throwing the deck into the
            air, picking the cards up at random, and repeating the process until the deck is sorted.
            Its name is a portmanteau the words bogus and sort.
        </item>
        <item>
            Insertion sort is a simple sorting algorithm that builds the final sorted array (or list) one item at a time.
            It is much less efficient on large lists than more advanced algorithms such as quicksort, heapsort, or merge sort. However, insertion sort provides several advantages:
            Simple implementation: Jon Bentley shows a three-line C version, and a five-line optimized version
            Efficient for (quite) small data sets, much like other quadratic sorting algorithms
            More efficient in practice than most other simple quadratic (i.e., O(n2)) algorithms such as selection sort
            or bubble sort Adaptive, i.e., efficient for data sets that are already substantially sorted: the time
            complexity is O(nk) when each element in the input is no more than k places away from its sorted position
            Stable; i.e., does not change the relative order of elements with equal keys
            In-place; i.e., only requires a constant amount O(1) of additional memory space
            Online; i.e., can sort a list as it receives it
            When people manually sort cards in a bridge hand, most use a method that is similar to insertion sort.
        </item>
        <item>
            Bubble sort, sometimes referred to as sinking sort, is a simple sorting algorithm that repeatedly steps
            through the list, compares adjacent pairs and swaps them if they are in the wrong order. The pass through
            the list is repeated until the list is sorted. The algorithm, which is a comparison sort, is named for
            the way smaller or larger elements "bubble" to the top of the list. Although the algorithm is simple,
            it is too slow and impractical for most problems even when compared to insertion sort. Bubble sort can be
            practical if the input is in mostly sorted order with some out-of-order elements nearly in position.
        </item>
        <item>
            Quicksort (sometimes called partition-exchange sort) is an efficient sorting algorithm, serving as a
            systematic method for placing the elements of an array in order. Developed by British computer scientist
            Tony Hoare in 1959 and published in 1961, it is still a commonly used algorithm for sorting.
            When implemented well, it can be about two or three times faster than its main competitors, merge sort
            and heapsort. Quicksort is a comparison sort, meaning that it can sort items of any type for which a
            "less-than" relation (formally, a total order) is defined. In efficient implementations it is not a stable
            sort, meaning that the relative order of equal sort items is not preserved. Quicksort can operate in-place
            on an array, requiring small additional amounts of memory to perform the sorting. It is very similar to
            selection sort, except that it does not always choose worst-case partition.
            Mathematical analysis of quicksort shows that, on average, the algorithm takes O(n log n) comparisons to
            sort n items. In the worst case, it makes O(n2) comparisons, though this behavior is rare.
        </item>
        <item>
            Cocktail shaker sort, also known as bidirectional bubble sort, cocktail sort, shaker sort (which can also
            refer to a variant of selection sort), ripple sort, shuffle sort, or shuttle sort, is a variation of
            bubble sort that is both a stable sorting algorithm and a comparison sort. The algorithm differs from a
            bubble sort in that it sorts in both directions on each pass through the list. This sorting algorithm is
            only marginally more difficult to implement than a bubble sort, and solves the problem of turtles in bubble
            sorts. It provides only marginal performance improvements, and does not improve asymptotic performance;
            like the bubble sort, it is not of practical interest (insertion sort is preferred for simple sorts),
            though it finds some use in education.
        </item>
        <item>
            Comb sort is a relatively simple sorting algorithm originally designed by Włodzimierz Dobosiewicz in 1980.
            Later it was rediscovered by Stephen Lacey and Richard Box in 1991. Comb sort improves on bubble sort.
            The basic idea is to eliminate turtles, or small values near the end of the list, since in a bubble sort
            these slow the sorting down tremendously.
            Rabbits, large values around the beginning of the list, do not pose a problem in bubble sort.
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sorts_code">
        <item>
            while (i  int_array.length) \"Iteration started\" {\n" +
                                if (int_array[i]  int_array[i-1]) {\n" +
                                    temp = int_array[i - 1];\n" +
                                    int_array[i - 1] = int_array[i];\n" +
                                    int_array[i] = temp;\n" +
                                    i = 1;\n" +
                                }\n" +
                                else {\n" +
                                    i++;\n" +
                                }\n" +
            \"Iteration started\"
                            }
        </item>
        <item>
            for(int i = 1; i int_array.length; i++) {" +
            "\n" + " for (int j = i; j > 0  int_array[j - 1] > int_array[j]; j&#8212;) {\n" + "&#8230; \n}
        </item>
        <item>
            int temp;\n" +
            "                for (int i = int_array.length - 1; i > 0; i&#8212;) {\n" +
            "                    for (int j = 0; j = i; j++) {\n" +
            "                        if (int_array[i-1] > int_array[i]) {\n" +
            "                            temp = int_array[i - 1];\n" +
            "                            int_array[i - 1] = int_array[i];\n" +
            "                            int_array[i] = temp;\n" +
            "                        }\n" +
            "                    }\n" +
            "                }
        </item>
        <item>
            int i = start, j = end;\n" +
            "        int stateElement = int_array[(i + j) / 2];\n" +
            "        int temp;\n" +
            "        while (i low= j) {\n" +
            "            while (int_array[i] low stateElement) {\n" +
            "                i++;\n" +
            "            }\n" +
            "            while (int_array[j] > stateElement) {\n" +
            "                j&#8212;;\n" +
            "            }\n" +
            "            if (i low= j) {\n" +
            "                temp = int_array[i];\n" +
            "                int_array[i] = int_array[j];\n" +
            "                int_array[j] = temp;\n" +
            "                i++;\n" +
            "                j&#8212;;\n" +
            "            }\n" +
            "        }\n" +
            "        if (start low j) {\n" +
            "            quickSort (start, j);\n" +
            "        }\n" +
            "        if (end > i) {\n" +
            "            quickSort (i, end);\n" +
            "        }
        </item>
        <item>
            int temp, left = 0, right = int_array.length - 1;\n" +
                            while (left = right) {\n" +
                                for (int i = left; i  right; i++) {\n" +
                                    if (int_array[i+1]  int_array[i]) {\n" +
                                        temp = int_array[i + 1];\n" +
                                        int_array[i + 1] = int_array[i];\n" +
                                        int_array[i] = temp;\n" +
                                    }\n" +
                                }\n" +
                                right&#8212;;\n" +
                                for (int j = right; j > left; j&#8212;) {\n" +
                                    if (int_array[j-1] > int_array[j]) {\n" +
                                        temp = int_array[j - 1];\n" +
                                        int_array[j - 1] = int_array[j];\n" +
                                        int_array[j] = temp;\n" +
                                    }\n" +
                                }\n" +
                                left++;\n" +
                            }
        </item>
        <item>
            final double DECREASE_FACTOR = 1.25;\n" +
                            int temp, space = (int)(int_array.length/DECREASE_FACTOR);\n" +
                            boolean noChanges = false;\n" +
                            while (!noChanges and (space > 0)) {\n" +
                                noChanges = true;\n" +
                                for (int i = 0; i + space  int_array.length; i++) {\n" +
                                    if (int_array[i] > int_array[i+space]) {\n" +
                                        temp = int_array[i + space];\n" +
                                        int_array[i + space] = int_array[i];\n" +
                                        int_array[i] = temp;\n" +
                                        noChanges = false;\n" +
                                    }\n" +
                                }\n" +
                                if (noChanges and (space > 1)) {\n" +
                                    noChanges = false;\n" +
                                }\n" +
                                space&#8212;;\n" +
                            }
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="sorts_debugs">
        <item>
            Stupid sort
            c = A (3)
            Loop while: c low= Z (4)
            - Iteration 1 (5)
            c = B (6)
            - Iteration 2 (5)
            c = C (7)
            - Iteration 3 (5)
            c = D (6)
        </item>
        <item>
            Insertion sort
            c = A (3)
            Loop while: c low= Z (4)
            - Iteration 1 (5)
            c = B (6)
            - Iteration 2 (5)
            c = C (7)
            - Iteration 3 (5)
            c = D (6)
        </item>
        <item>
            Bubble sort
            c = A (3)
            Loop while: c low= Z (4)
            - Iteration 1 (5)
            c = B (6)
            - Iteration 2 (5)
            c = C (7)
            - Iteration 3 (5)
            c = D (6)
        </item>
        <item>
            Quick sort
            c = A (3)
            Loop while: c low= Z (4)
            - Iteration 1 (5)
            c = B (6)
            - Iteration 2 (5)
            c = C (7)
            - Iteration 3 (5)
            c = D (6)
        </item>
        <item>
            Cocktail Shaker sort
            c = A (3)
            Loop while: c low= Z (4)
            - Iteration 1 (5)
            c = B (6)
            - Iteration 2 (5)
            c = C (7)
            - Iteration 3 (5)
            c = D (6)
        </item>
        <item>
            Comb sort
            c = A (3)
            Loop while: c low= Z (4)
            - Iteration 1 (5)
            c = B (6)
            - Iteration 2 (5)
            c = C (7)
            - Iteration 3 (5)
            c = D (6)
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="category_0">Sorts</string>
</resources>
